Hunmin Yang (양훈민)

Personal Website Senior AI Researcher @ ADD PhD Candidate @ KAIST

Yuseong P.O. Box 35, Daejeon 34186, Republic of Korea 291 Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon 34141, Republic of Korea

Research Interest

• Trustworthy Machine Learning & Computer Vision

o My research focuses on developing safe and reliable artificial intelligence to enable safe model deployment in real-world applications. To achieve this, I work at the intersection of machine learning and computer vision. My current interests include transferable adversarial attacks, domain generalization, and representation learning.

Experience

Agency for Defense Development (ADD)

Daejeon, Korea Jan 2020 - Present

Email: hmyang@kaist.ac.kr

Mobile: +82-10-8447-1009

Senior AI Researcher

• D-CAM: Adversarial attack & defense techniques for robust AI

• D-GEN: Synthetic data generation framework for training AI

Agency for Defense Development (ADD)

AI Researcher

Daejeon, Korea May 2017 - Dec 2019

o D-NET: Large-scale AI inference platform with Hadoop-Spark

Agency for Defense Development (ADD)

Specialized Research Staff (Military Service)

Daejeon, Korea Feb 2014 - May 2017

EDUCATION

Korea Advance Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Korea Sep 2021 - Present

PhD in Mechanical Engineering

o Research Area: Machine Learning & Computer Vision

o Advisor: Kuk-Jin Yoon

Korea Advance Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Korea Feb 2012 - Feb 2014

MS in Mechanical Engineering

o Research Area: 3D Sound Perception

o Advisor: Youngjin Park

Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology (RMIT)

Exchange Student (High Distinction)

Melbourne, Australia Feb 2011 - Aug 2011

Korea Advance Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

BS in Mechanical Engineering (Magna Cum Laude)

Daejeon, Korea Feb 2007 - Feb 2012

PUBLICATIONS

- Hunmin Yang, Jongoh Jeong, Kuk-Jin Yoon. Prompt-Driven Contrastive Learning for Transferable Adversarial Attacks. In European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2024. (Oral, top 2.3%)
- Junhyeong Cho, Kim Youwang, Hunmin Yang, Tae-Hyun Oh, Object-Centric Domain Randomization for 3D Shape Reconstruction in the Wild. In IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshop on Foundation Models, 2024.
- Hunmin Yang*, Jongoh Jeong*, Kuk-Jin Yoon. FACL-Attack: Frequency-Aware Contrastive Learning for Transferable Adversarial Attacks. In Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2024.
- Junhveong Cho, Gilhvun Nam, Sungveon Kim, Hunmin Yang, Suha Kwak. PromptStyler: Prompt-driven Style Generation for Source-free Domain Generalization. In IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023.
- Naufal Suryanto, Yongsu Kim, Harashta Tatimma Larasati, Hyoeun Kang, Thi-Thu-Huong Le, Yoonyoung Hong, Hunmin Yang, Se-Yoon Oh, Howon Kim. ACTIVE: Towards Highly Transferable 3D Physical Camouflage for Universal and Robust Vehicle Evasion. In IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023.

- Hunmin Yang, Se-Yoon Oh, Junhyeong Jo. Synthetic Image Generation for Deep Neural Networks. In *NVIDIA GPU Technology Conference (GTC)*, 2023. (Spotlight)
- Naufal Suryanto, Yongsu Kim, Hyoeun Kang, Harashta Tatimma Larasati, Youngyeo Yun, Thi-Thu-Huong Le, **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh, Howon Kim. DTA: Physical Camouflage Attacks using Differentiable Transformation Network. In *IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2022.
- Jeonghun Kim, Kyungmin Lee, Hyeongkeun Lee, **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh. Camouflaged Adversarial Attack on Object Detector . In 21th International Conference on Control, Automation and Systems (ICCAS), 2021.
- Hunmin Yang, Se-Yoon Oh, Taewon Kim, Ki-Jung Ryu. D-GEN: A Deep Learning Data Generation Framework For Artificial Intelligence. In NVIDIA GPU Technology Conference (GTC), 2020.
- Kyungmin Lee, **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh. Adversarial Training on Joint Energy Based Model for Robust Classification and Out-of-Distribution Detection. In 20th International Conference on Control, Automation and Systems (ICCAS), 2020.
- Eunchong Kim, Kanghyun Park, **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh. Training Deep Neural Networks with Synthetic Data for Off-Road Vehicle Detection. In 20th International Conference on Control, Automation and Systems (ICCAS), 2020.
- Hyeongkeun Lee, Kyungmin Lee, **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh. Applying FastPhotoStyle to Synthetic Data for Military Vehicle Detection. In 20th International Conference on Control, Automation and Systems (ICCAS), 2020.
- Kanghyun Park, Hyeongkeun Lee, **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh. Improving Instance Segmentation using Synthetic Data with Artificial Distractors. In 20th International Conference on Control, Automation and Systems (ICCAS), 2020.
- Hunmin Yang, Se-Yoon Oh, Ki-Jung Ryu. Accelerating Distributed Deep Learning Inference on multi-GPU with Hadoop-Spark. In NVIDIA GPU Technology Conference (GTC), 2019. (Oral)
- **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh, Ki-Jung Ryu. Scalable Distributed Deep Learning Inference on Multi-GPU with Hadoop-Spark. In *NVIDIA GPU Technology Conference (GTC)*, 2019.
- Se-Yoon Oh, **Hunmin Yang**, Ki-Jung Ryu. Optimal Distributed Inference on Multi-GPU Processing System. In NVIDIA GPU Technology Conference (GTC), 2019.
- Se-Yoon Oh, **Hunmin Yang**, Ki-Jung Ryu. Optimal Experimental Design Approach for Machine Learning Process. In 17th International Conference on Control, Automation and Systems (ICCAS), 2017.

PATENTS

Machine Learning & Synthetic Image Generation

- Hunmin Yang, Se-Yoon Oh. Training data generation method and apparatus for deep learning model. kr 10-2613781, 2023.
- Hunmin Yang, Ki-Jung Ryu, Se-Yoon Oh. Apparatus and method for deep learning based on mixing virtual and real data. kr 10-2198088, 2020.
- **Hunmin Yang**, Ki-Jung Ryu, Se-Yoon Oh. Apparatus and method for learning machine learning models based on virtual data. kr 10-2086351, 2020.
- Hunmin Yang, Se-Yoon Oh, Seongbaek Jo. Apparatus and method for enhancing learning capability for machine learning. kr 10-2053202, 2019.
- Hunmin Yang, Ki-Jung Ryu, Se-Yoon Oh. Method and apparatus of improving self-supervised learning performance utilizing synthesized data. kr 10-2032519, 2019.
- Hunmin Yang, Ki-Jung Ryu, Se-Yoon Oh. Method and Apparatus of adding artificial object for improving performance in detecting object. kr 10-1972095, 2019.
- **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh, Seongbaek Jo. Apparatus and method for generating learning image in game engine-based machine learning. kr 10-1947650, 2019.

AI Security & Adversarial Robustness

- Se-Yoon Oh, **Hunmin Yang**, Hyeongkeun Lee, Kyungmin Lee, Jeonghun Kim. Method and Apparatus for optimizing adversarial patch, computer-readable storage medium and computer program. kr 10-2445215, 2022.
- Hyeongkeun Lee, Jeonghun Kim, Kyungmin Lee, **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh. Method and Apparatus for optimizing adversarial patch, computer-readable storage medium and computer program. kr 10-2414146, 2022.

- Jeonghun Kim, Se-Yoon Oh, Hyeongkeun Lee, Kyungmin Lee, **Hunmin Yang**. Apparatus and method for optimizing adversarial patch based on natural pattern for stealthiness against human vision system. kr 10-2380154, 2022.
- Hyeongkeun Lee, Hunmin Yang, Jeonghun Kim, Kyungmin Lee, Se-Yoon Oh. Method, apparatus computer-readable storage medium and computer program for determining adversarial patch position. kr 10-2360070, 2022.

Big Data & Database

- Hunmin Yang, Ki-Jung Ryu, Se-Yoon Oh. Method and apparatus of building NoSQL database for signal processing. kr 10-2002360, 2019.
- **Hunmin Yang**, Ki-Jung Ryu, Se-Yoon Oh. Method and apparatus of building inverse index DB for high speed searching of moving picture object. kr 10-2014267, 2019.

Honors and Awards

Selected as Oral Presentation (top 2.3%)

Oct 2024

- In European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)
 - o Prompt-Driven Contrastive Learning for Transferable Adversarial Attacks

National Grant for Defense Research and Development

Dec 2021

- From the Chief Director of DAPA
 - $\circ\,$ Synthetic Data Generation for Defense AI

Defense Science Award

Aug 2019

- From the Chief Research Director of ADD
 - o Improving Distributed Multi-GPU Computing for Large-scale Video Analytics

High Achievement Award

Aug 2018

- From the Chief Research Director of ADD
 - o Big Data Platform Development and Synthetic Data Generation

Excellent Paper Award

 $Mar\ 2013$

- From the Korea Society for Noise and Vibration Engineering (KSNVE)
 - o Sweet Spot Analysis of Linear Array System by Geometrical Approach

Scholarship for Academic Excellence

Jun 2007

- From the Korea Human Resource Development Scholarship Association
 - o Outstanding Academic Performance

Scholarship for Academic Excellence

2007-2014

- From the Korean Government
 - Tuition free for all semesters in KAIST (BS & MS)

Professional Services

• Academic Reviewer

- IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)
- $\circ\,$ IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)
- European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)

• Technology Transfer

- \circ Synthetic data generation for training AI models \to SI Analytics, Jcorp System, JEIOS
- \circ Physical adversarial camouflage generation for attacking AI models \to SmartM2M
- $\circ~$ Big data platform for large-scale AI model inference \rightarrow XIIIab